CV

Herbert Flor

Urban Planning + Design

herbert.flor@yahoo.com +971 56 433 6391

Experience in Every Design Step

Experience in GIS-based site analysis and thematic mapping analysis; concept development, preparing various options, hand-drawn or Illustrator graphics, based on project requirements; refining the preferred option; master plan development; creating engaging visuals of the master plan, both 2D illustrated plan and 3D rendered model of the whole site; putting everything together in a report and presentation format.

Skills

Design

Site Analysis | Concept Design | Urban Design | Master Plan | Urban Renewal | Design Guidelines

Involved in all aspects of planning, from concept development, preliminary master plan stage and detailed design stage.

- Prepared site analysis diagrams illustrating existing conditions, future developments, connections, topography and aerial imagery using ArcGIS
- Created design concepts for large and small projects, using handdrawn sketches or Adobe Illustrator graphics.
- Performed community facilities calculation and distribution, land use plan and open space network and strategies.
- Urban design studies of cluster and neighborhood centers and public realm, including diagrams illustrating urban design strategies for placemaking, walkability, pedestrian and vehicular circulation and landscape strategy.
- Coordinated with other disciplines for review of roads, traffic and utility requirements.

Selected Projects

- Developed Structure Plan Concept for a 18,000 ha project site using a polycentric approach with residential-commercial center, hospitality and recreation center and business park.
- Designed detailed master plans with total combined areas of over 300 ha.
- Public Realm / Urban Design Studies for 3 urban areas.

Graphics

Adobe Creative Suite | Photoshop | Illustrator | InDesign | After Effects

Professional History

Ras Al Khaimah Municipality

Senior Urban Planning Specialist 2014-Present

Parsons Corporation, Dubai

Junior Urban Planner CADD Supervisor CADD Draftsman 2005-2014

Parsons Corporation, Doha

CADD Draftsman 2004-2005

Parsons Corporation, Manila

Associate Designer 2001-2002

Skills

Design

Graphics

3D Modelling and Rendering

Reports and Presentations

CADD

GIS

HTML and CSS

Education

Bachelor of Science in Architecture

Bicol University, Philippines 2000

License & Certification

Architect

Philippine Professional Regulation Commission (PRC) Jan. 2001 PRC No. 16456

Affiliation

- Highly skilled on graphic presentation using Adobe Suite.
- Used various programs to create concept illustrations, illustrated master plan, urban design strategy diagrams, motion graphics and video presentation.
- Created a 3-minute video presentation that is used as a marketing material for a master plan development in Ras Al Khaimah.

3D Modeling and Rendering

3ds Max | Vray | Sketchup

- Highly proficient 3D modeling and animation.
- Created and rendered a full 3D of a 400-ha master planned site including roads, buildings, streetscapes, parks and other community facilities. The rendered images were used as marketing materials.
- Created animated 3D characters using Adobe Maximo for use in fly-through animation.
- Created fly-through animation of whole site and various elements using 3ds Max and Vray plugin.
- Stitched together a 3-minute video, with motion graphic titles, notes and music using Adobe After Effects.

Reports and Presentations

InDesign | PowerPoint

- Used InDesign to create reports and manuals including the Addressing Manual which is being used to implement first ever addressing system to the whole emirate of Ras Al Khaimah.
- Used InDesign and other graphic programs to create Design Guidelines.
- Used PowerPoint to present to management various projects and proposals.
- Presentations are always well received that one manager described it as like "watching a BBC documentary."

CADD

AutoCAD | MicroStation | Bentley MX Roads

- Excellent AutoCAD and MicroStation skills.
- Created a workflow to convert MicroStation files to AutoCAD, thereby saving several manhours of manual conversion.
- Used Bently MX Roads to create a 3D model of a hilly site. The 3D model was then brought to 3ds Max and used as a base to model and render the project site.

Geographic Information System (GIS)

ArcGIS Pro | ArcMap | Thematic Mapping Analysis

- Proficient in using ArcGIS Pro to quickly create various thematic mapping analysis for project sites.
- Uses ArcGIS Pro modelbuilder to facilitate repetitive workflows.

United Architects of the Philippines (UAP)

Member, 2001-Present

Distinction

8th Placer Licensure Examination for Architects

Philippine Professional Regulation Commission (PRC) Jan. 2001